

Professional Summary

Creative and proactive Frontend Engineer with more than 3+ years of experience in building stable and responsive websites, collaborative environments. Highly skilled in HTML, CSS and JavaScript frameworks. Team player able to work in a multidisciplinary and multicultural environment with a passion for usability and responsive design.

Soft Skills

- Teamwork
- Time management
- Problem solvin
- Adaptable
- Creative
- Self-management
- Lateral thinking
- Divergent thinking
- Self-Motivated
- Active listening

Programming Skills

- HTML5
- CSS3 SaSS
- JavaScript
- Vue Js
- React Js
- React Native
- Bootstrap
- GitLab/GitHub
- Doduy
- O T.
- OpenTok

- Python
- Node Is
- API REST
- API GraphQL
- Apollo
- mySQL
- Google Cloud
- Jira
- React Native
 Firebase

Language

- English
 Level C1 Advanced Fluency
- **Spanish** *Mother Tongue*
- Italian
 Level A1 Currently studying

Agustina Ruidiaz

FRONTEND ENGINEER

Contact Details

Address: Via Degli Studi 65 - Pozzallo (Ragusa), Italy

Mobile: +39 351 8941623

Email: agusruidiaz@hotmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/agusruidiazgd

LinkedIn: /agusruidiaz

Work Experience

REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER

UMA Health Feb 2021 - Feb 2022

- **Project**: App mobile for Telemedicine platform for booking medical consultation appointments, self diagnostic with AI and machine learning.
- Development and distribution of native apps (both for Android and IOS) using React Native (Firebase DB) - in line with ES6 good practices.
- Authentication, Firebase DB, Crashlytics and analytics
- Implementing machine learning with front end development
- Mobile Development with framework React Native (Typescript), including integration with Redux and Firebase.
- Unit testing (Jest for React)
- Worked with Xcode iOS Dev Program to build and conduct A/B testings (TestFlight)
- Use of native tools with Gradle, Android Studio and Google Play Console in order to create .apk and test them.

SEMI SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Octosoft Professionals Feb 2021 - Current

- Projects: Virtual library application, NFT Gallery Marketplace, Landings.
- Associate partner in the development area for projects with React Js, Gatsby and Meterial UI
- Provided training and guidance to new hires
- Adapted to the client's ongoing changes while providing results on a tight deadline
- Incentivized live work sessions in order to create a unified workplace

Education ADA ITW

400hs course - Febrary 2020 - October 2020

- HTML5 CSS3 (Sass processor)
- React Js
- Vanilla JavaScript
- Jest (testing)

UTN (NATIONAL TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY)

Bachelor's in Textile Engineering - March 2014 - March 2020

• Textile Engineering Degree (Complete)

Courses and Workshops

Agile Scrum

May 2020 - KUBADILI

 Fundaments and UX Methodology July 2020 - CHISPA LAB

Figma (prototype / layout)